# Lukin Maksim, Software Engineer, web, linkedin, github, email

Feb 19, 1990, Eastern Europe, Married

#### **Experience:**

## — Golang/Ruby on Rails developer at <u>Dentsply Sirona</u> (2020 - present)

Building Golang + gRPC API (8 month - present), also using Ruby on Rails for the Atlantis Web Order global web site used by clinicians and laboratories to order dental implants and abutments.

Deployment and automatization tools, enhancing existing codebase and development processes (1 year).

## — Ruby on Rails developer & IT consultant at <u>Lukin.io</u> (2018 – 2020, **2y**)

Helping business and companies to grow by consulting, developing and supporting using Software Engineering practices, designing API.

Working as Senior Engineer using Ruby (and Rails), NodeJS/React, designing API, consulting clients, monitoring, developing tools using best practices.

# — Ruby/JS Engineer, Team Lead/PM at <u>Facewatch</u> (2013 – 2018, **5y**)

Backend development using Ruby and Sinatra. Small services based on Ruby on Rails. API based on service oriented architecture, Amazon services. Frontend based on BackboneJS. Integration with Metropolitan Police (London), Facial recognition using external API. Security Audit/PenTests. Writing RSpec tests and documentation. Implement new API.

## — iOS Engineer at <u>iaccomo</u>, <u>EVENTAGRATE</u> (2012 – 2013, **1y**)

Developing corporate applications for iPad, bluetooth messenger for conferences. Porting from Java/Swing application to iOS application. Development of jPass application.

### — Ruby on Rails developer at GAP Intelligence (2009 – 2011, 2y)

Backend/Frontend development of DataCenter v2. DevOps tasks.

## Interests:

Open Source, GO, Ruby, learning new technologies, self-development.

#### Education:

Hardware Engineering faculty (Professional College of Computer Science, 2003-2006).

#### Summary:

Writing clean, <u>SOLID</u> code. Tests, automated tests, CI/CD, Amazon services.

Experience in development with Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, API, Redis, Sidekiq

Understanding Frontend-related side, HTML/CSS, JS (TypeScript, ReactJS, Redux, Backbone.js);

DevOps basic skills (Linux, Chef/Ansible, Docker);

Had experience in iOS development, NodeJS;

Agile/Scrum, TDD/BDD;